<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Grungeons And Groblins]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/</link><image><url>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Grungeons And Groblins</title><link>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 21:39:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 21:39:43 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[BennBolton]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>BennBolton</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Character Creation]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Starting at Level 5 so characters have some sort of individual adventuring experience before the party meets
<br>Use point buy for initial ability scores
<br>Roll for health or take the given amount, up to you
<br>For every ASI level, take an ASI and a feat
<br>Can change spell casting ability (INT, WIS, CHA) if still works thematically and isn't broken (speak to me)
<br>Optional class features are allowed
<br>Ask first about specific Unearthed Arcana or Homebrew stuff
<br>Choose to start with gold or look at item prices in standard shops and "buy" stuff before the campaign begins (speak with me about choice of items)
<br>Can use extended alignment chart if you wish. Keep your alignment in the top left 3x3<br>
<img alt="5x5 Alignment Chart" src="https://i.pinimg.com/474x/d5/aa/69/d5aa69cb9923fd676d98e9109a2042e1.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
<br><br>
<br>Each start with 2 magic item tokens, use them to give your character magic items to start with. 
<br>Choose 2 Common or one Uncommon magic item from any source you find just check with me about them when choosing
<br>Bag of Holdings are in short supply and are not readily available in the current economy
]]></description><link>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/-wiki/the-beginning/character-creation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">- Wiki/The Beginning/Character Creation.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[BennBolton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 20:52:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://i.pinimg.com/474x/d5/aa/69/d5aa69cb9923fd676d98e9109a2042e1.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.pinimg.com/474x/d5/aa/69/d5aa69cb9923fd676d98e9109a2042e1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[House Rules]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Ordinarily not tracking food and water
<br>Will be tracking encumbrance via magic Alex spreadsheet
<br>Potions (both drinking and using on someone else) will be item interactions
<br>Long rests can only be taken in safe areas (bedroom or a safe camp etc)
<br>Every time you fall to zero HP you take a level of exhaustion
<br>Obvious action checks can only be tried by two people e.g. a lock will jam up after the second person has failed to pick it. (Group Perception) (Case by Case)
]]></description><link>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/-wiki/the-beginning/house-rules.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">- Wiki/The Beginning/House Rules.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[BennBolton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 20:53:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The World]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><img alt="- Images/Iroda(Regioned)-min.png" src="https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/lib/media/iroda(regioned)-min.png"><br><br>Set in the High Fantasy Medieval continent of Iroda...<br>For as long as anyone can remember, the world has been under the steady hand of the gods, with Ronos reigning as the King of the Cosmos. His influence is woven into everyday life – freedom of will and personal ambition are celebrated as divine virtues, shaping societies that value independence, exploration, and self-determination above all else.<br>Civilisation has thrived for centuries under this divine order. Great cities flourish, trade flows through bustling merchant guilds, and The Boundless Concord ensures the ideals of freedom remain protected. Stability and peace have endured for generations, with no great wars or upheavals in living memory.<br>The common folk live with a sense of freedom and stability, trusting that the world they’ve inherited will continue unchanged. Yet, beneath the surface, the winds of uncertainty have begun to stir.<br><br>Ronos is the King of the Gods, Benevolent Ruler of Iroda, God of Freedom. He is acknowledged as the supreme god, with other "lesser" gods, acting as his appointed divine servants. He allows them to maintain domains such as war, harvest, love, and craftsmanship.<br><br>
<br>The Boundless Concord<br>
The most prominent faction in all of Iroda: usually referred to as just "The Concord", these are the devout followers of Ronos, but is more than just a religious faction - it’s a movement. Its followers believe that true freedom comes not only from external liberty but from inner clarity and the courage to defy destiny itself. They view Ronos not just as a distant god-king but as a symbol of personal empowerment and the relentless pursuit of one’s own path. They look down on those who worship other gods even though they work under Ronos' name.<br>
The concord works closely with the governments in all major cities to ensure the people of Iroda remain "free". With large armies and lots of resources into knowledge and the arts. They are the faction of the people.
<br>The Gilded Ledger<br>
A powerful and far-reaching merchant guild that controls vast trade networks, ensuring the flow of goods, coin, and influence across the realm. They are known for their strict contracts and unwavering enforcement of debts. While most transactions involve gold, rumours persist of more secretive dealings – whispers of bargains sealed with something deeper than wealth. It is said that, for those with the right connections, the Gilded Ledger offers alternative forms of payment – though few understand what that truly means, and fewer still speak openly of it.
<br>The Verdant Pact<br>
A druidic alliance dedicated to protecting nature from over-expansion and exploitation. Keeping to themselves most of the time - they are respected in rural areas but sometimes clash with cities over land use and deforestation.
<br>The Azure Tide<br>
A powerful maritime guild of sailors, traders, and privateers that controls much of the seafaring commerce. Some consider them noble explorers, others see them as opportunistic smugglers hiding behind a powerful name.
<br>The Iron Guild<br>
A coalition of the best blacksmiths, miners, and craftsmen, who control the production of weapons, armour, and construction materials. Their influence ensures that kings and warlords alike depend on their supply lines.
<br><br><br>In common knowledge, the magic in the world is described using the metaphor of an endless ocean. Casters have found varying ways to tap into the magic, named Virilis. Some being born with it running through their veins, others engineering "taps" to access and expend it. Learned casters (wizards, bards, druids etc) are highly respected as good at their trade, natural casters (sorcerers, innate etc) are perceived as lucky individuals, feared by some, respected by others. Warlocks are looked down upon as unworthy and unnatural by other casters. Magic is not rare, but not common, with<br><br>
<br>The Ancient Gods:<br>
There are stories of an ancient pantheon of gods whose names have been passed down through childhood stories and schooling (like the Ancient Greek Gods are to us). Some prominent names include: Edra of fate, Nidona of death, Ithar of the sea, Seraphina of magic. Some say they guided the world with wisdom, while others claim they meddled too much in the affairs of mortals, binding them to an unseen order. In time, their influence waned and their temples crumbled. No one knows if they were destroyed, left of their own will, or simply faded into legend. Now, only scattered ruins and half-remembered stories hint at the gods who once were, their purpose and power long forgotten.
<br>The Curse of the Ninth Onion:<br>
It is said that if a farmer harvests the very last vegetable in a patch, misfortune will follow for nine days. To avoid this, farmers always leave a single crop behind, ensuring that the field is never truly empty. Over time, this tradition became so ingrained that even in abandoned or overgrown fields, one can often spot a lone vegetable left behind - for luck, for respect, or simply for fear of tempting fate.
<br>The Seven:<br>
Legend tells of Seven Brothers, imbued with divine power to take down a malevolent God. But ambition corrupted some, and the brothers turned on each other in a tragic battle. The purest of them, strengthened by the Liberator’s gift, banished the corrupted kin to a shadowed realm and watched over cities for centuries after, rumoured to be protecting something.
<br>The Star That Fell Sideways:<br>
A shooting star once fell not from the sky, but sideways across the horizon, cutting through the world like a blade. Villages near the fall reported strange visions and heard whispers of a realm not meant for mortals. Folklore says that if you stand on the highest peak during a meteor shower, you might hear that same whisper – though none can agree on what it says. Some believe it promises fortune, others fear it’s a warning from something ancient and patient.
<br>The Feast of the Endless King:<br>
In forgotten times, a mighty king hosted a banquet so lavish that it never ended. Food replenished itself, goblets refilled unbidden, and guests danced forever in eternal revelry. But soon, they discovered they could no longer leave. The palace faded from mortal sight, and traveler's claim that, on misty nights, you can hear faint music from the hills. It’s said that if one stumbles upon the Endless King’s feast, they must leave before the third song ends – or risk joining the revellers forever.
<br>The Creation of the Goblinoids:<br>
Long ago, three warriors were sculpted by the gods, each meant to embody strength, cunning, and leadership. But before they were granted true wisdom, a trickster spirit whispered false knowledge into their unfinished minds, and they rose too soon. The first became a brute who relied only on strength, the second a sly scavenger who thrived on trickery, and the third a warlord who thought himself wise but lacked true foresight. Cast out and abandoned, they spread across the land - one a lurking predator, one a scheming thief, and one a commander doomed to overconfidence and failure.
]]></description><link>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/-wiki/the-beginning/the-world.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">- Wiki/The Beginning/The World.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[BennBolton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 20:58:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/lib/media/iroda(regioned)-min.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/lib/media/iroda(regioned)-min.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grungeons and Groblins]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>This site should hopefully document all important information that I give you throughout the campaign (If i remember to update it properly). See below for quick links:<br>]]></description><link>https://bennbolton.github.io/GrungeonsAndGroblins/-wiki/landing-page.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">- Wiki/Landing Page.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[BennBolton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 20:52:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>